<TXT>
870123-0009.
Eastern Air Proposes Date
For Talks on <COREF ID='-5'><COREF ID='-5'>Pay-Cut Plan</COREF></COREF>
01/23/87
WALL STREET <COREF ID='-7'>J</COREF>OURNAL (<COREF ID='-7'>J</COREF>)
LABOR TEX
AIRLINES (AIR)
<COREF ID='-11'>MIAMI</COREF>
<COREF ID='3' REF='-7'>Eastern Airlines</COREF> executives notified <COREF ID='-13'>union leaders</COREF> that <COREF ID='-14'><COREF ID='-14'>the carrier</COREF></COREF> wishes to discuss selective wage reductions on <COREF ID='6' REF='-5'>Feb. 3</COREF> .
Union representatives who could be reached said <COREF ID='8' REF='-11'><COREF ID='9' REF='-13'><COREF ID='-20'><COREF ID='-19'>they</COREF></COREF></COREF></COREF> hadn't decided whether <COREF ID='8' REF='-11'><COREF ID='9' REF='-13'><COREF ID='-20'><COREF ID='-19'>they</COREF></COREF></COREF></COREF> would respond.
By proposing <COREF ID='10' REF='-20'><COREF ID='-21'><COREF ID='-21'>a meeting date</COREF></COREF></COREF> , <COREF ID='11' REF='-21'>Eastern</COREF> moved one step closer toward reopening current high-cost contract agreements with <COREF ID='12' REF='-14'>its unions</COREF> .
The proposal to meet followed <COREF ID='-27'>an announcement</COREF> <COREF ID='-28'>Wednesday</COREF> in which Philip Bakes, <COREF ID='14' REF='-3'>Eastern's president</COREF> , laid out proposals to cut <COREF ID='-31'>wages selectively</COREF> an average of 29%.
<COREF ID='18' REF='-3'>The airline</COREF> 's three major labor unions, whose <COREF ID='-36'>contracts</COREF> don't expire until year's end at the earliest, have vowed to resist the <COREF ID='19' REF='-27'>cuts</COREF> .
Nevert<COREF ID='20' REF='-19'>he</COREF>less, one union official said <COREF ID='20' REF='-19'>he</COREF> was intrigued by t<COREF ID='20' REF='-19'>he</COREF> brief and polite letter, which was hand-delivered by corporate security officers to t<COREF ID='20' REF='-19'>he</COREF> unions .
According to Robert Callahan, <COREF ID='22' REF='-28'>president of Eastern's flight attendants union</COREF> , the past practice of Eastern's parent, Houston-based <COREF ID='25' REF='-21'>Texas Air Corp.</COREF> , has involved confrontation and ultimatums to <COREF ID='26' REF='-5'>unions</COREF> either to accept <COREF ID='27' REF='-31'>the carrier</COREF> 's terms or to suffer the consequences -- in this case, perhaps, layoffs.
"Yesterday's performance was a departure," <COREF ID='28' REF='-60'>Mr. Callahan</COREF> said, citing the invitation to conduct broad negotiations -- and <COREF ID='-60'>the lack of a deadline imposed by management</COREF>.
"Frankly, <COREF ID='29' REF='-36'>it</COREF> 's a l<COREF ID='29' REF='-36'>it</COREF>tle mystifying."
</TXT>